《闪电侠》本季回顾
This season on "The Flash"...
-你是谁  -我叫杰伊·加里克
- Who are you? - My name is Jay Garrick.
在我的世界里  我也是个极速者
Where I came from, I was a speedster like you.
在我到达你们地球之前
Before I arrived on your Earth,
我在跟一个叫极速的人打斗
I was in a fight with a man named Zoom.
他会不惜一切代价
He will do whatever it takes
来确保他在所有的世界里是唯一的极速者
to ensure he's the only speedster in any world.
永远别忘了
Never forget:
我是现今世上速度最快的人
I am the fastest man alive.
我有时候会有些感觉  这些震波
I get these feelings sometimes, these vibes.
-西斯科  你看见什么了  -我看见杰伊了
- Cisco, what did you see? - I saw Jay.
他就是极速
He's Zoom.
那个戴铁面具的人是谁
Who's the man in the iron mask?
说了你也不会相信的
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
你觉得如果
What do you say
你和我再给彼此一次机会怎么样
you and I give this a shot?
好  我很希望这样
Yeah, I would like that.
我通常利用计算受害者数
I've always measured my success
来衡量我的胜利
by counting the number of victims I've had.
但现在我要扩大范围了
But now I think I'm going to start counting
换成计算我征服的地球数
the number of Earths I conquer instead.
地球2号裂成了两半
Earth-2 is splitting in half.
告诉我  我刚才没有看到世界末日
Tell me I did not just see the end of the world.
-爸爸  不  别  -而这会让你变得
- Dad? No. No! - This is what's gonna make you
和我一样
just like me.
-杰伊  -不
- Jay? - No!
不
No!
爸爸
Dad?
看着我  看着我  爸爸
Hey, look at me. Look at me. Dad.
别离开我  不要再这样  爸爸
Don't leave. Not again. Not again. Dad!
坚持住  坚持住
Come on. Come on. Come on.
没事的  不要
It's all right. No.
爸爸
Dad.
不要  爸爸
No, Dad.
我告诉过你  家人就是弱点
I told you family was a weakness.
你感觉到了愤怒  是不是  闪电侠
You feel the anger, don't you, Flash?
现在
And now...
我们俩是一样的了
the two of us are the same.
不  不
No! No!
就是这样  闪电侠  运用你的愤怒
There you go, Flash! Use your anger,
就像我一样
just like I did.
你逃不掉了  佐勒蒙
I got you, Zolomon!
来吧  巴里
Go on, Barry.
释放你的怒火
Embrace your anger.
结果我
End me!
我来帮你下手吧
Let me do it for you.
就差一点  巴里
So close, Barry.
又是时间残余
Another time remnant.
你看  巴里
You see, Barry,
世上可能有两个你
there could be two of you.
你只需要愿意杀死你自己
You just have to be willing to kill yourself.
没错
Yeah.
你就快准备好了
You're almost ready.
今日抚慰我们
And comfort us today
用您的承诺之词
with the word of your promise
在我们将亲人送回大地的同时
as we return our brother to the earth,
亨利·艾伦
也给我们留下了期许
and leave us with the hope
诺拉·艾伦
那就是  有一天我们会重逢
that, one day, we'll meet again.
我父亲是...
My father's...
我现在做不到
I can't do this right now.
没事的  巴里
It's okay, Barry.
亨利·艾伦
Henry Allen.
亨利这一生经受了两次重大的失去
Henry suffered two great losses in his life.
他失去过妻子诺拉  也失去过巴里
He lost his wife, Nora, and he lost Barry.
他遭受过罪恶感
He suffered guilt,
窘迫
embarrassment,
嘲笑  耻辱  以及一切
ridicule, shame, and everything that
因无辜蒙冤伴随而来的痛苦
comes with being blamed for a crime he didn't commit.
亨利·艾伦充分证明了
Henry Allen was proof that
爱能伴你走过最黑暗的岁月
love can get you through the darkest of days,
这种爱也会让他永远活在我们所有人心里
and that love will keep him alive in all of our hearts.
我会抓住他的  爸爸
I'm gonna find him, Dad.
我发誓会让他
I promise you I'm gonna take from him
为这一切付出代价
what he took from you.
我觉得你或许该吃点东西
I thought maybe you should eat something.
谢谢  不过我不饿
I'm not hungry. Thank you, though.
好吧
Yeah.
巴里
Barry, um...
我之前并不知道你就是闪电侠
I had no idea that you were The Flash.
你为我做的
What you did for me,
你为每个人  为这个城市
all the things that you've done for everyone,
做了那么多...
this whole city...
现在你爸爸却遭极速下此毒手
And now this with your dad and Zoom.
我非常遗憾
I'm so sorry.
谢谢你  沃利
Thanks, Wally.
如果你有任何需要
If there's anything you need,
尽管开口
you just say the word.
好的
All right.
各位
Guys,
极速依旧逍遥法外
Zoom's still out there.
我们必须制定一个计划
We need to come up with a plan.
那家伙能打开去地球二的缺口
The man can crack open breaches to Earth-2.
他有如此能耐
I mean, if he can do that,
谁知道他还能做出什么
what else can he do that we don't know about?
他干掉自己的时间残余后
Right after he killed his time remnant,
对我说  我"就快准备好了"
he told me I was "almost ready."
准备好做什么
Almost ready for what?
我不知道
I don't know.
你看  典型的疯子
Yep. Classic psychopath.
就不能直接说出自己的意图吗
Why can't they ever just say what they want to do?
我们还得搞清楚  我为何总是感知到地球二
We also have to figure out why I keep vibing Earth-2
四分五裂的景象
being ripped to shreds.
真的吗
Seriously.
仿佛在看4D版的《变形金刚》
It's like I'm watching "Transformers" In 4-D,
但是比那要真实十倍
but, like, ten times more realistic
而且效果逼真多了
and with much better acting.
如果你能用震波感知未来
Look, if you can vibe the future,
我们要在那之前阻止极速
we need to stop Zoom before that happens.
我去透透气
I'm gonna get some air, all right?
我去陪他
I got it.
我在神速力之中的时候
When I was in the Speed Force,
我觉得
I felt like
我终于能坦然接受她的死
I'd finally come to grips with her death,
接受自己回到过去却没有救她
with not saving her when I went back.
结果恰好就在...
And then the moment...
在我终于能够放下过去时
where I'm finally at the place I can move on,
我的父亲又被夺走了
my father's taken from me.
这让我如何能够平静以对
How am I ever supposed to find peace with that?
我也不知道  巴里
I don't know, Barry,
但你一定要想办法做到
but you're gonna have to find a way to do that,
不然这会让你崩溃的
or it's gonna tear you apart.
我现在已经非常想念他了
I just miss him so much already.
是极速
Zoom.
巴里  别去
Barry, no!
不太好过吧  闪电侠
Bad time, Flash?
我想应该给你一些时间哀悼
Thought I'd give you some time to mourn.
现在就做个了断吧
This ends now.
还不是时候
Not yet.
我能带走的还有很多  巴里
There's always more to take, Barry.
你给我离他们远点
You're gonna stay away from them.
那完全取决于你
Well, that's completely up to you.
什么
What?
我们初次见面的时候
When we first met,
我告诉你极速要成为最强
I told you that Zoom needed to be the best.
你只是没有意识到我是在说我自己
You just didn't realize I was talking about myself.
你来找我就是为了这个吗
Is that what this is about?
来比一场吧  巴里
A race, Barry,
你我之间
between you and me...
看看谁才是最快的
to see who's the fastest.
你赢了的话  一切尘埃落定
You win, this is over,
你继续当你的英雄
and you get to be the hero.
我不会和你比的
I'm not racing you.
那么你父亲就不会是唯一那个我从你身边
Then your father won't be the only person you love
夺走的你所爱之人
that I'll take from you.
想想吧  闪电侠
Think about it, Flash.
我只是想知道在这两个世界里谁才是
All I want to know is who's the fastest man alive
跑得最快的人
on either world.
我等着你
I'll be waiting.
所以极速想和你比赛吗
So Zoom wants to race you?
他痴迷于成为最强
He's obsessed with being the best.
我们为什么要相信他
Why would we trust him?
他只是想要比赛
He just wants to race.
你知道的  按照一种完全疯狂的
You know, it actually makes sense
方式来看这件事其实还挺讲得通的
in a completely-off-your-rocker sort of way.
他想要的不可能只有这么点
That can't be everything he wants.
确实不止
It isn't.
水星实验室开发的这颗磁星
This Magnetar that's being developed by Mercury Labs--
原来是可以充当脉冲星来使用的
turns out, it can act as a pulsar.
脉冲星是什么
What is a pulsar?
是一种拥有强磁化致密旋转内核的
It's a power amplifier with a highly magnetized,
功率放大器
dense rotating core
并且极易被武器化
that can be easily weaponized.
那还真是一点都不危险
Nah, that's not dangerous at all.
这就是发生在地球二上的事
That's what happens to Earth-2.
我震波看到的事情就是因为这件机器
What happens in my vibes is because of this machine.
那玩意强大到可以摧毁一颗行星了吗
That thing is powerful enough to destroy a planet?
如果配上合适的能量源
A lot more than just a planet,
它能摧毁的可不仅仅是一颗行星
if it has the right power source.
比如什么能量源
Like what?
比如我
Like me.
这就是他想比赛的原因
That's why he wants to race.
他想要吸取我跑起来的时候创造出的能量
He wants to siphon the energy I create when I run.
他想吸取你们俩的能量
He wants to siphon the energy off both of you.
杰伊囚禁我的时候
When Jay captured me,
他说他曾经以死在他手里的受害者人数
he said that he used to measure his success
来判定他自己的成功程度
by counting the number of victims he had,
但是现在他换了另外一种方式
but now he was gonna measure it
以他征服的地球数量来判定成功程度了
by counting the number of Earths he conquered instead.
他不仅仅想毁灭地球二
He doesn't want to just destroy Earth-2;
他想毁灭这个多元宇宙里的所有其他行星
he wants to take out every other planet in the multiverse.
有多少颗行星
How many are there?
无限颗
Infinite.
是啊  那么他能做到吗
Yeah, well, he can do that?
如果他可以自己创造出连接地球二的缺口
If he can create a breach to Earth-2 all on his own...
他就可以连接所有地球
He can get to all of 'em.
用脉冲一次全部摧毁
One pulse to destroy them all.
我猜我别无选择
I guess I don't have a choice.
我必须得和他比赛
I have to race him.
而且必须得赢
And I have to win.
巴仔
Bare.
别跟他比
Don't race him.
这事可没那么简单
It's not that easy.
就是这么简单  你只要拒绝就行
Yes, it is. You just say no.
我们再找其他办法阻止他
We find another way to stop him,
我们齐心协力  就像一直以来一样
together, like we always do.
然后怎么办  乔
And do what, Joe?
就坐等着他继续杀人吗
Just sit around and wait for him to kill somebody else?
沃利  爱瑞丝  你
Wally? Iris? You?
不  不行
No. No way.
他需要你  巴仔
He needs you, Bare.
他需要你的速度来实现目的
He needs your speed again to get what he wants.
优势在我们手里
We have the advantage here.
只要我战胜他就可以了  乔
All I have to do is beat him, Joe.
那样能拯救多元宇宙  救这座城  救你们
That saves the multiverse, this whole city, all of you.
我不会再让我爱的人死去
I won't let another person I love die
尤其当我能阻止的时候
when I can prevent it.
这...
This...
不仅仅是为了和极速赛跑吧
isn't just about racing Zoom, is it?
你想要杀了他
You want to kill this guy.
我当然想要杀了他  乔
Of course I want to kill him, Joe.
我想要的远远不止杀了他
I want to do a hell of a lot more than just kill him.
我想要他为所做的一切受苦
I want him to suffer for everything that he's done.
他一定会的
And he's going to.
冷静点  巴仔
Come on, Bare.
想想你说的话
Think about what you're saying.
我必须要不惜一切代价才行
I have to be willing to do whatever it takes.
抱歉  但我要和他赛跑
I'm sorry, but I'm racing him,
不管你是否同意
whether you want me to or not.
我也说不通你了吗
And I can't talk you out of it?
这次不行
Not this time.
那我也抱歉了
Then I'm sorry too.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
为什么把我关在这里
Why did you put me in here?
因为你现在处于愤怒之中
Because you're too angry right now.
你不能这样和他赛跑
You can't race him like that.
毫无计划  你会输的
Without a plan, you're-- you'll lose.
把我关在这会害死所有人
Keeping me in here is gonna get everyone killed.
只有我能阻止他  你们知道的
I'm the only one that can stop him, you know that.
你按他的意图赛跑
You race Zoom on his terms,
你会输的
you'll lose.
这不是你们说了算的
This is not your decision to make!
这次是的
It is this time.
不
No.
我们一起做的决定
We all made it together.
什么
What?
所有人
All of you?
兄弟  我也考虑很久
Bro, I went back and forth.
一开始我还左右为难
I was, like, a good 60/40 at first.
拉蒙
Ramon.
是的  我们一起做的决定
Yeah, yeah, we all made the decision.
不是吧
Come on.
艾伦
Allen.
这是为了你好
This is for your own good.
别这样
Don't do this.
大伙  拜托  爱瑞丝
Guys, come on. Iris?
西斯科  拜托
Cisco, come on, man.
你们必须让我去
You have to let me--
你们必须让我去阻止他
you have to let me stop him!
你们必须让我去
You have to let me...
我们的决定正确吗
Did we make the right call here?
是正确的
Yeah, we did.
你没事吧  乔
You okay, Joe?
没事  只是比我预想的要难些
Yeah, that was just a little harder than I anticipated.
是啊  关住巴里...
Yeah, locking up Barry...
还算容易的部分
That was the easy part.
巴里不在  用我们的计划干掉极速
Now, using our plan to take down Zoom without Barry,
才是困难的部分
that's gonna be the hard part,
但知道他在哪的话
but it's gonna be a lot easier
会简单许多  拉蒙
once we know where he is, Ramon.
别着急  伙计  我正在找
Chill, man. I'm working on it.
再加把劲
Work harder.
找到了
Got it.
追踪完成
他在利伍德路的工业园里
He's at the industrial park on Leawood.
-击个掌  -好
- Give me that. - Yep.
这呆子还真有爱
That is some serious nerd love right there.
斯诺
Snow.
听我说  如果你不想经历这个
Look, everybody here would understand
大家都会理解的
if you don't want to go through with this.
杰伊虽然是个怪物
Jay may be a monster,
但是他内心里还有人性
but there's a human inside of him somewhere
我之前唤起过他的人性
I've gotten to that part of him before.
我知道我还能做到
I know I can do it again.
我想要阻止他  哈里
I want to stop him, Harry,
永远地阻止他
for good.
拉蒙
Ramon.
我们再重复一遍计划
So let's go over the plan again.
好的  凯特琳分散杰伊的注意力
Okay, Caitlin will distract Jay
这样你和哈里就能用靴子向他开火了
so that you and Harry can hit him with the boot.
然后西斯科打开缺口
Cisco's gonna open the breach,
我们把他扔进去
and we're gonna put him through it.
解除磁星的武器
I'll disarm the Magnetar.
毁掉磁星...
Destroy the Magnetar...
拯救多元宇宙
save the multiverse.
还有一件事  我们要达成一致
One more thing. We need to agree.
这是我们共同的决定
We all made this decision together,
所以即使出了什么意外  我们也要坚持下去
so if anything goes wrong, we stick with it.
整装待发吧
Let's load up.
怎么了
What's the matter?
我一直在想
You know, I've just been thinking.
接下来会发生什么
You know, what's-- what's next?
会发生什么
What's next?
就是阻止极速
We stop Zoom.
是啊
Right.
是啊  我想...
Right, I guess...
我是说  这事了结以后
I don't know, I mean-- after that.
我也不知道  我真没怎么想过这事
I don't know. Haven't really given it much thought.
是的  我知道你没想过
Yeah, no-- no, I know you haven't.
我只是  我只是最近一直在想这事
Guess I've just--I've been thinking about it a lot lately.
我能看出你跟这里的人相处得很好
You know, I see the way you are with everyone here
凯特琳和西斯科
Caitlin and Cisco,
爱瑞丝和乔
Iris and Joe,
巴里
Barry,
尤其是巴里
especially Barry.
你非常关心他们
You care about these people a lot.
可是  可是我的朋友们
You know, but-- but my friends?
他们都在我们那个地球上
They're all back home on our Earth.
我想我要说的是
I guess what I'm trying to say is,
等这一切都结束以后
you know, when this is all over,
我要回家去
I'm gonna go back home
过我的生活
to live my life.
但如果你想待在这里
But if you need to stay here
重新开始自己的生活  我也理解
so that you can live yours again, I get that.
我能理解的  没关系  因为
I understand. It's okay, because--
-我...  -不  爸爸
- I... - No, Dad.
你能开心
Seeing you happy,
才是我最期待的
that is all I've ever wanted for you.
好了  已就位
Okay. In position.
收到  我们收到了
Copy that. We got you.
好的  斯诺  你准备好了吗
Okay. Snow, you ready?
我已尽力做好准备
As ready as I can be.
西斯科  西斯科  你还好吗
Cisco. Cisco, you good?
什么算"好"
Define "good."
拉蒙  你没问题的
Ramon. You're gonna be great.
斯诺
Snow.
准备好了就出发
When you're ready.
好的
Okay.
你行的
You got this.
那就来吧
Here we go.
杰伊
Jay?
凯特琳
Caitlin.
杰伊
Jay!
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
麦吉博士说有人从她实验室里偷走了磁星
Doctor McGee said the Magnetar was stolen from her labs.
我就知道一定是你
I knew that it had to be you,
所以我查到你在这里
so I tracked you here.
只有我查到你在这里  杰伊
I tracked you here, Jay.
其他人不知道
No one else knows.
我和你说过  如果你离开我
I told you, if you left me--
如果我背叛你  你不会对我仁慈  我知道
That if I betrayed you, you'd show me no mercy, I know.
但我只是想解释我为什么离开你
But I just want to explain why I did that.
听我说  杰伊
Please, Jay.
说
Talk.
干得好
Good job, girl.
现在  慢慢靠近他
Now draw him towards you.
我做错了
I made a mistake.
很对不起我抛下了你
I am so sorry that I abandoned you.
但你必须明白
But you have to understand,
你对我说
what you said to me
我有邪恶的一面
that there was a dark side of me
我更像冰霜杀手  而我全然不知
that I was more like Killer Frost than I knew--
我不想接受这一点
I didn't want to accept that.
我尽力把我的邪恶面锁起来
I tried to lock the darkness inside of me.
但是你知道那现在已经成为了我的一部分
But you knew that that was already a part of me now.
而且只有你知道
And you're the only one who did.
现在
And now,
我准备好接受真实的自己
I'm ready to accept who I really am.
西斯科  做好准备
Cisco, get ready.
很对不起我伤害了你
I am so sorry that I hurt you.
但现在我想成为只有你了解的人
But now I want to be the one that only you know.
求你  杰伊
Please, Jay.
让我试试
Let me try.
再向前走一步
One more step.
我就知道你最终会想通的  凯特琳
I knew you'd eventually come around, Caitlin.
可惜太迟了
But it's too late.
就是现在  拉蒙
Now, Ramon!
糟了
Damn it.
用药麻醉他
Tranq him!
枪卡住了
Gun is jammed!
成功了
It's working.
爸爸
Dad!
看到我爸爸了吗
Did you see my dad?
没  震波一直在转换
No, the vibe keeps changing.
就像是我的大脑不停地转换频道似的
It's like my brain is channel surfing or something.
他们肯定在移动
They must be on the move.
所以震波不停地在转变
That's why the vibe's in flux.
继续试
Keep trying.
你关闭磁星了吗
Hey, did you turn off the Magnetar?
没  别乱弄那东西
No, there's no messing with that thing.
不管他怎么弄的  我们试着触碰它
Whatever he did to it-- we try and touch it,
试着移动它  在这星球上都用不了了
we try and move it-- this planet's done for.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
极速抓走了爸爸
Zoom took Dad.
什么  怎么会
What? How?
我们逼他穿越缺口  想要阻止他
We tried to stop Zoom by pushing him through the breach,
但是他把乔一起带走了
but he took Joe with him.
巴里呢  他去追了他了吗
Well, where's Barry? Did he go after him?
他没和我们一起  他被关在牢房里
He's not with us. He's in a cell in the intake.
等等  你们试图独力阻止极速吗
Wait, you-- you tried to stop Zoom alone?
说来话长
Long story.
我们得把他弄回来
Well, we have to get him back.
沃利  在极速抓走爸爸之前
Wally, before Zoom took dad,
我们都同意了如果把他赶出这个地球
we all agreed that if we got him off this Earth,
我们就永远关闭缺口
we would close the breaches for good,
而且再也不打开它们
and we would never open them again,
无论发生什么
under any circumstances.
为什么  你们为什么要这么做
Why-- why would you do that?
不  没门  这绝对不行
No. No way, that's not gonna happen.
他让我们都同意了
He made us all agree to it.
好吧  你猜怎么着  我没同意
Well, guess what. I didn't agree to that.
沃利
Wally--
爱瑞丝  我已经失去了我妈妈
Iris, I already lost my mom.
如果爸爸
If dad...
我
I--
我得说
I will say,
巴里确实有足够多的爸爸可以杀
if anything, Barry sure has an ample number of fathers to kill.
如果你想杀我的话
If you're gonna kill me,
就杀吧
kill me.
无所谓的
It doesn't matter.
没有人和你比赛
You're not racing anybody.
别这样  乔
Come on, Joe.
你很了解巴里  是你把他养大的
You know Barry better than that. You raised him.
如果他觉得可以救你  那他一定会同意的
He'll say yes if he thinks he can save you.
这次可不一样
Not this time.
我确保了这事不会发生
I made sure of it.
那是谁
Who is that?
真相只会让你感到困惑
It would just confuse you.
说来听听
Try me.
我得到速度的方式和巴里一样
I got my speed the same way Barry did.
当我被暗物质和电流击中的时候
When I got struck by the dark matter and electricity,
我变成了极速  现今世上速度最快的人
I became Zoom, the fastest man alive.
不久之后  这个地球就对我俯首称臣
Wasn't long before I had this Earth on its knees.
但那还不够
But it wasn't enough.
我还想要更多
I wanted more.
我想变得更快
I wanted to be faster.
所以我创造了一种神速药
So I created a speed drug.
终极速度-9
Velocity-9.
它让我变得不可想像得快
It made me faster than I ever thought possible,
快到足以打破维度障碍
fast enough to break the dimensional barrier,
快到足以跑到其他宇宙里去
fast enough to run to other universes,
其他地球上
other Earths.
然后有一天  在其中的一个地球上
And then, one day, on one of those other Earths,
我发现了他
I discovered him.
他也是一个极速者
He's another speedster?
是的  你可以这么说
Yeah, you could say that.
那时候我正好也发现了其他的事情
That was right about the time I discovered something else too.
我注射进体内的那些
All that V-9 I'd been injecting
终极速度-9有一点副作用
into my system had a little side effect.
它在杀死你
It was killing you.
我寻找过解药
I searched for a cure.
我试过了一切方法
I tried everything.
我甚至试着去操控神速力
I even tried to manipulate the Speed Force,
但让我告诉你  神速力
but let me tell you, the Speed Force,
神速力不喜欢它的规则被打破
the Speed Force does not like its rules being broken.
此后它就开始派它的执法者来追杀我
Now it's been sending its enforcers after me ever since.
所以你带他到这来偷他的速度
So you brought him here to steal his speed.
我试过了  但没有成功
I tried, but it wouldn't take.
但之后天空就裂开了
But then the skies parted,
然后我看见了巴里
and I saw Barry,
然后我就偷走了他的速度
and then I stole his speed.
我赢了
I won.
我战胜了神速力的规则
I beat the rules of the Speed Force.
为什么把他留在这
Why keep him here?
作为战利品
Trophy.
也作为我的消遣
And a little idea I had for fun.
我厌倦当反派了
You see, I got so tired of being the villain,
所以我决定我也要当英雄
so I decided to be the hero too.
我甚至借用了他的名字
I even borrowed his name,
杰伊·加里克
Jay Garrick.
你知道最棒的会是什么吗  警探
You know what's gonna be great, Detective?
等我在比赛中打败巴里
After I beat Barry in the race
并且证明自己是现今世上速度最快的人之后
and prove that I'm the fastest man alive on any Earth,
他会在笼子中腐烂
he's gonna rot in a cage
就像杰伊现在待的那个笼子一样
just like the one Jay's in now.
然后就会有来自两个世界的闪电侠
And then I'll have a Flash from two worlds
陪着我了
to keep me company.
听着
Look.
等大家发现我这么做了之后他们都会发疯的
Everyone's gonna freak when they find out I did this,
但我不在乎
but I don't care.
我们需要你的帮助  巴里
We need your help, Barry.
伙计们
Hey, guys,
巴里不在...
Barry's not...
他的牢房里了
in his cell anymore.
沃利
Wally!
怎么  我不能就这样无动于衷任由这事发生
What? I wasn't just gonna stand here and let this happen.
你让他绑走了乔
You let him take Joe?
你在想些什么
What the hell were you thinking?
艾伦  我们无能为力
Allen, there was nothing we could do.
你本可以让我和他比一场的
You could've let me race him!
艾伦  你不能和极速比
Allen! You're not racing Zoom!
你打算怎么办  再把我迷晕一次吗
What are you gonna do? Are you gonna tranq me again?
不要逼我
Don't tempt me.
听着  我知道你们约定要让极速待在地球二
Look, I know you guys made a pact to keep Zoom on Earth-2,
但你们根本没经过我和沃利的同意
but you did that without me and Wally.
你们不能那样做
All right? You don't get to do that!
巴里  看看你现在的样子  你的状况不好
Barry, look at yourself right now. You're not okay.
西斯科  我爸爸刚刚在我面前被杀
Cisco, my dad was just killed in front of me!
你知道那是什么感觉吗
Do you have any idea how that feels?
看着自己爱的人死亡的感觉吗
Watching someone you love die?
我知道
Yes, I do.
凯特...
Cait--
听着  巴里
Look, Barry.
我清楚那种感觉可以让你变得
I know how cold and angry
很冷漠  很愤怒  让你拒人千里之外
and distant that can make you.
但当我变成这样时
But when this happened to me,
是你把我拉了回来
you were the one who kept me in check.
你制止了我  让我好好缓缓
You told me to stop and take a breath,
我们现在也只是希望你能做到这一点而已
and that's all we're telling you to do now.
我说了我没事
I'm telling you I'm good.
真的吗  你没事吗
Really? You're good?
因为在我看来你不光是想阻止极速
Because it seems to me you want to do more than stop Zoom.
在我看来你是想报仇
It seems to me you want revenge.
假如这是你的初衷
If that's why you're doing this,
艾伦  你会输的
Allen, you will lose.
伙计们  听着
Look, you guys.
我...  你们也许觉得我做不到
I-- you may not think I can do this.
你们也许觉得我被怒火蒙蔽了
You may think I'm too angry.
但我们就快没时间了
But we're running out of time!
我必须得打败他
I have to beat him,
我也要去打败他
and I'm going to,
无论你们是否帮助我
whether I have your help or not.
你们到底帮不帮我
So which one is it?
这东西是怎么运作的
So how does this work?
和我们让爱瑞丝进入神速力是一个道理
It's the same way we took Iris into the Speed Force.
哈里好好扮演科学怪人
Harry does his best Frankenstein,
你拉住我的手  我把你震过去
you hold my hand, and I vibe you there.
好吧  开始吧
All right, let's do it.
我应战
I'll do it.
告诉我时间地点  我会到场的
Say when and where. I'll be there.
西斯科学会如何把别人带进他的震波里了啊
Cisco's learned how to bring people into his vibes.
只有一个条件
There's one condition.
你放了乔
You bring Joe back.
但他必须毫发无伤
But if he's harmed in any way,
否则就取消
it's off.
我会带他回去
I'll bring him,
但得等我们比赛后才能放了他
and I won't release him until after we race.
成吗
Deal?
成
Deal.
听我说  杰伊或许很疯癫
I tell you, Jay might be crazy-pants,
但他很会挑场地
but he can pick a venue.
全员出动  是吗
Brought the whole crew with you, huh?
也不能怪你
Can't say I blame you.
-爸  -沃利
- Dad. - Wally!
这肯定非常精彩
It's gonna be one hell of a show.
放了他
Let him go.
比完了再放
After we race.
少废话  我们知道你打算启动磁星
Cut the crap. We know you plan to power up the Magnetar
毁掉多重宇宙
so you can destroy the multiverse.
不错  差点就被你
Bravo. You figured it out...
发现了
almost.
我不想毁了一切
I don't want to destroy all of it.
这个地球是多重宇宙的中心
This Earth is at the center of the multiverse.
从这里可以到达现存的所有地球
It's the access point to every other Earth in existence.
只需一次超维冲击波  便化为灰烬
One trans-dimensional shockwave, and...poof.
只留下我们的地球
Leaving just our Earth.
你可真大方
How generous of you.
总得找个地方让我大展身手
Need to have some place to hang my cowl.
你或许想道个别
You might want to say your good-byes.
别担心
Don't worry.
我会救下你们的爸爸
I'm gonna save your dad.
不
No.
你会救下咱们的爸爸
You're gonna save our dad.
回尖端科技研究实验室  那里更安全
Get back to S.T.A.R. Labs. It's safer.
我们哪都不去
We're not going anywhere.
我们就要在这里守着
We got eyes and ears right here.
要么他走
Either he goes,
要么咱们同归于尽
or we all die together.
我们相信你
We believe in you.
等等
Wait.
巴里
Barry,
痛扁他
kick his ass.
告诉我规则
What are the rules?
在圆圈内跑一圈
One lap around the inside of this loop
会产生一千兆瓦的能量
will produce about 1 gigawatt of energy,
我需要五百倍的能量
and I need 500-plus to power the Magnetar
来启动磁星
enough to do the job.
一旦能量饱和  我就赢了
Once it's full, I win,
因为无人能阻止
because there is no stopping it.
那我要打败你
So all I have to do to beat you
就要赶在能量饱和前
is stop you before that happens.
对  就这么简单
Yep. It's that simple.
如果你没完成比赛
But if, at any point, you decide you don't want to race anymore,
你的二号老爸和小粉丝团
dear old dad number two is a dead man,
就都死定了
as well as your little fan club.
他们不是我的粉丝团
They're not my fan club.
我为他们奔跑
They're the reason that I'm running,
为他们打败你
why I'm gonna beat you.
那就给我看看你的能耐  闪电侠
Let's see what you're made of, Flash.
说开始吧  极速
Just say when, Zoom.
跑吧  巴里
Run, Barry.
跑
Run!
他要启动磁星了
He's powering up the Magnetar.
快  巴里  追上他
Come on, Barry. Catch up.
哪个是巴里
Which one's Barry?
两个都是
Both of them.
-他制造了... -时间残余
- He made a... - Time remnant.
快走  快走
Go, all right? Go!
我等下再解释  乔
I'll explain later, Joe.
残余
A remnant?
偷学我的招数  闪电侠
Stole my trick, Flash.
可你已经来不及了
But you're too late.
再见了  多重宇宙
Bye-bye, multiverse.
不
No!
那个时间残余体在干什么
What's the time remnant doing?
他在制造自己的脉冲
He's creating his own pulse.
-他为什么要那么做  -因为...
- Why would he do that? - Because...
如果产生异相
if that's out of phase,
就可以抵消掉
it'll counteract that one.
慢着  他的身体承受不了
Wait, his body can't handle that.
接下来会发生什么
Then what's gonna happen?
他会死
He'll die.
不
No!
你是个英雄  巴里
You're a hero, Barry.
你之前没能杀掉我
You couldn't kill me before.
现在也动不了手
You won't kill me now.
我不必自己动手
I don't have to.
所以你穿越到过去
Okay, so you ran back in time
然后造出了自己的副本
and made a copy of yourself?
差不多
Well, uh, basically.
对
Yeah.
那叫时间残余
It's called a time remnant.
我不能经常那么干
It's not something that I can do every day,
可我得想办法把时间亡灵
but I needed a way to draw the Time Wraiths
从神速力中引出来
out of the Speed Force,
希望极速的所作所为
hoping they'd be more upset
比我做的更能惹火他们
at what Zoom had done than they'd be with me.
他们谈论科学理论时
Is that what I look like
我就是那个表情吗
when they start talking about science?
半斤八两
Pretty much.
别愁  沃利
Don't worry, Wally.
以后你会慢慢理解的
It'll get easier to understand.
那怎么能做到呢
Well, how does that even work?
和极速一样
Same way Zoom did it.
我穿越到我离开前的时刻
I ran back in time moments before I left.
只有这样我才能同时出现在两个地方
It's the only way I can be in two places at once.
好  所以时间残余还是你
Okay, so the time remnant, it's still you?
对
Yeah.
可他死了
But he died.
他愿意为了大家牺牲自己
He was willing to sacrifice himself for all of us.
他就是那么爱我们
That's how much he loved us.
好了  我们别管这些了
You know what? We'll just-- we'll forget about it.
巴里  我很开心你没事
Barry, I'm glad you're okay.
你们知道吗
You know what?
上战场要挑好武器
In battle, choose your weapon wisely.
对吧  有的人选择用枪
All right? Some people choose a gun.
我会选十字螺丝起子
I choose a Phillips-head screwdriver.
抱歉  你太挑剔了
I'm sorry. You're so particular.
拉蒙  能麻烦你...
Ramon, can you just please--
你之前用过工具吗
have you ever worked with a tool before?
现在正用着呢
I'm working with one now.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
一
One,
二
two,
接着...
and...
我不知道哪个更烦人
I don't know what's more annoying,
是被那东西困着
being in that thing
还是听你俩争执
or listening to you two arguing about it.
你是...
You're--
我是杰伊·加里克
I'm Jay Garrick,
真正的杰伊·加里克
the real Jay Garrick.
怎么了
What?
抱歉  我很抱歉
I'm sorry. I--I'm sorry.
巴仔
Bar...
他长得很像他
He looks just like him.
他长得很像我爸爸  乔
He looks just like my dad, Joe.
我无法相信
I can't believe this.
我爸爸告诉过我
My dad told me.
他告诉过我
He told me this. He said
他母亲的娘家姓是加里克
his mom's maiden name was Garrick.
我只是完全没想到
I just never thought that that meant--
-巴里  巴里  -我只是完全没想到
- Barry, Barry. - I never thought it meant--
巴里  他不知道
Barry, he doesn't know that.
他不知道
He doesn't know
他是你爸爸的二重身  好吗
that he's your dad's doppelganger, okay?
你要我告诉他你必须离开吗
You want me to tell him that you had to leave?
不需要
No. No.
你确定吗
You sure?
是的
Yeah.
我需要冷静一下
I just need a minute.
我会没事的
I'll be all right.
-真聪明  -就因为...
- That's smart. - Because of--
-是啊  就是那样  -天才
- Yeah, and there it is. - Genius.
你无法使用你的超能力
So the reason you didn't have your powers
是因为面具里有个抑制器
is because there was a dampener in the mask.
看见了吗
You see?
我不想再看见这个东西
I don't want to see this thing ever again.
所以你找回你的超能力了
So your powers are back.
我看杰伊  不对  是亨特
I see Jay-- excuse me--Hunter--
还偷了你的配色
stole your color scheme too.
他取走了我很多东西
He took a lot of things that were mine,
除了那个
except for that.
那个完全属于他
That's, um-- that's all him.
他说是他父亲打战时戴过的
He said it was his father's from the war.
真讽刺  在我...我们的地球
Ironically, on my--on our Earth--
这个头盔代表希望
this helmet stood for hope.
-是吗  -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
也许我可以延续这个情操
Well, maybe I can continue that sentiment,
也取走他一些东西
take something from him, for a change,
当作是我自己的
make it my own.
跟你很合适
It suits you.
谢谢大家
Thank you, all of you,
从极速手中把我救出
for saving me from Zoom,
特别是你  闪电侠
especially you, Flash.
不用客气
You're welcome,
闪电侠
Flash.
现在我必须想办法回家
Now all I have to do is find my way home.
在哪里呢
And where's that?
我想你们会叫它地球三
I think you would call it Earth-3.
我可以送你去地球二
Well, I can get you to Earth-2.
之后我跟我女儿会帮你
My daughter and I can help you with the rest.
我们能吗
We can?
是  我们能
Yes, we can.
我们要回家了
We're going home.
好吧
Okay.
斯诺
Snow.
你是个非常出色的科学家
You're a tremendous scientist, but...
但你是个更好的人
you're an even better person.
别弄我哭  哈利
Don't make me cry, Harry.
我已经哭了太多次了
I've done enough of that already.
乔·韦斯特警探
Detective Joe West...
哈利
Harry.
你的孩子很棒  照顾好他们
You have great kids. You take care of them.
你也是
Same to you.
把这个漂亮女孩照顾好
You take care of that beautiful girl.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
来了这里之后我变成更好的人了
I'm a better man than I was when I got here,
都是你的功劳
and that's 'cause of you.
我何尝不是
I'm not the same either.
如果你有时
Hey, don't be surprised
在地球二看到我
if I project myself over to Earth-2
不要感到意外
every once in a while, you know,
我只是把你的东西送过去
just to throw your stuff across the office.
我也会想你的  西斯科
I'll miss you too, Cisco.
我不能在另一个地球给你发短信吧
So I guess I can't text you from another Earth, huh?
我想不能了
I guess not.
那太糟糕了
That's too bad.
由衷感谢大家
Thank you guys, seriously,
拯救了我的家园
for saving our home.
准备好了吗
Ready?
好了
Yeah.
我不禁会想起我爸爸的二重身
Can't stop thinking about my dad's doppelganger.
看着他  知道他活着
Seeing him, knowing that he's out there,
本该让我释怀些
that should've made it easier.
但不是
It doesn't.
我反而更想念他
It just made me miss him even more.
我无法想像你内心的痛苦
I can't even imagine how hard that must have been.
我们赢了
We just won.
我们打败极速了
We just beat Zoom.
我为什么有挫败感
Why does it feel like I just lost?
因为你失去了很多  巴里
Because you've lost a lot in your life, Barry,
实在太多了
more than most.
但...
But...
也许我和你
Maybe you and me
一起面对
seeing where this thing goes,
也许能改变你的生活
maybe that can give you something for a change.
我一直希望听到你说这句话
That's all I've ever wanted to hear you say.
我希望我能
And I wish that I was in a place
试着跟你在一起
where I could try that with you.
但现在我的内心是空虚的
But I feel so hollowed out inside right now.
我从来没这么撕心裂肺过
I feel more broken than I've ever felt in my life.
如果我要跟你坠入爱河
If I'm ever gonna be worth anything to you,
我必须把自己调整好
I need to fix what's wrong with me.
我必须让自己平静
I need to find some-- some peace.
巴里  听我说
Barry, listen to me.
你等了我那么多年
You waited for me for years.
你让我知道我们可以尝试
You let me get to a place where this was possible.
现在我告诉你
So I am telling you
我也会为你这么做
I am gonna do the same thing for you.
不管你要去哪里
Wherever you need to go,
不管你要做什么
whatever you need to do,
都行
do it.
我会在这里等你回来
And when you get back, I'll be here.
好
Okay.
我爱你  巴里
I love you, Barry.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我会一直爱着你
And I always will.
所以我很抱歉
That's why I'm so sorry.
但我必须这么做
But I have to do this.
-巴里  -妈妈
- Barry! - Mom!
巴里
Barry!
不要
No! No.
这次你杀不了她了
You're not gonna kill her this time.
你再也杀不了她了
You're not gonna kill her ever again.
不
No.
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
知道吗
Okay?
你安全了
You're safe.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.